Guide to the Paul Langland Papers, 1926-2018 MSS.253
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: Photographs, 1965-2011; 220856
  - Tour in Germany, 1986; 221782 (Binder 11)
    15 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Stephen Petronio, 1986; 1988; 1998; 221783 (Binder 11)
  - Expo- Vancouver, 1986; 221784 (Binder 11)
  - Lee Nagin, Joyce Theater, 1987; 221785 (Binder 11)
  - World Trade Center, 1987; 221786 (Binder 11)
  - [David Zambrano], 1988; 1990; 1998; 2000; 2010; undated; 222079 (Binder 12)
  - Meredith Monk Tour- Geneva, Amsterdam, 1989; 222080 (Binder 12)
    30 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Scott Heron, 1989; 1990; 1996; 2000; 2009-2011; 222081 (Binder 12)
    11 photographs
  - Robert Flynt Photographs, 1988; 1990-1993; 1997; 1998; 222082 (Binder 12)
    22 photographs, 2 negatives, 3 slides
  - Ghost of a Flea, 1989; 222083 (Binder 12)
    4 photographs, 3 contact sheets
  - Boomerang, 1989; 222084 (Binder 12)
    20 photographs, 1 slide
  - Photoshoot for Normal Kansas, 1990; 222085 (Binder 13)
    24 photographs
  - Photoshoot for Downtown Upstate, 1990; 222086 (Binder 13)
  - Headshots, 1990; 222087 (Binder 13)
  - American Dance Festival- Seoul, 1991; 222088 (Binder 13)
    20 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Experimental Theater Wing, NYU, 1991; 1993; 1994; 1998; 1999; 2005; 2009; 2011; 222089 (Binder 13)
    27 photographs
  - Contact Improvisation and Channel Z, 1993; 222090 (Binder 13)
  - Diane Torr, 1993; 1999; 2005; 222092 (Binder 14)
  - First outfall Workshop- California, 1993; 222093 (Binder 14)
    15 photographs
  - Normal Kansas, 1994; 222094 (Binder 14)
    1photograph
  - Cuba, 1994; 222095 (Binder 14)
    14 photographs
  - Full Flora Smak, 1994; 222096 (Binder 14)
    36 photographs
  - Almost Rapture, 1996-1998; 222097 (Binder 14)
    15 photographs, 3 negatives
  - Almost Rapture, 1997; 222098 (Binder 14)
    1 photograph, 5 contact sheets
    Photographs by Robert Flynt
  - Almost Rapture, 1997; 222110; - (Binder 14)
    9 Photographs, 4 contact sheets, 4 negatives
    Photographs by Tom Brazil
  - Honor, 1998; 222100 (Binder 15)
    13 photographs
  - Honor, 1998; 222101 (Binder 15)
    30 photographs, 5 negatives
    Photographs by Paula Court
  - Circus Amok- Coney Island, 1999; 222102 (Binder 15)
    26 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Heat, 2000; 222103 (Binder 16)
    20 photographs, 7 contact sheets, 2 negatives
  - September 11, 2001, September 12, 2001; 222104 (Binder 16)
    24 photographs, 2 pages of negatives
  - Paul and Colin's Wedding, 2009; 222105 (Binder 16)
    28 photographs
  - P.S. 122 Photoshoot, undated; 222106 (Binder 16)
    3 contact sheets
  - Gail Turner, undated; 222107 (Binder 16)
    3 contact sheets1 photograph
  - [Album 1], circa 1977-1979; 222115 (Binder 17)
    84 photographs
  - [Album 2], circa 1977; 222117 (Binder 17)
    98 photographs
- Series IV: Posters, Programs and Flyers, 1964-2011; 220858
  Series IV consists of posters, programs, and flyers for various dance and arts performances and events. It largely consists of material related to New York City venues from the mid 1970s through the 1990s, but also includes other localities. Included in this series is material related to many notable New York City performance spaces and groups, including Danspace, Dance Theater Workshop LaMama, and Movement Research. Due to the nature of the type of material, many of the posters, programs and flyers do not include a year.
  Series IV is arranged into two subseries, reflecting Paul Langland's original organization. Subseries A is arranged by artist and Subseries B is arranged by venue. Any additional material that was not assigned an original category has been arranged alphabetically by venue. This material appears at the end of the series.
  - Subseries A: Artists, 1964-2008; 222140
    - Laurie Anderson, 1983; undated; 222379 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Pina Bausch, undated; 222380 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - John Bernd, 1978-1979; 1988; 222381 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Eric Bogosian, 1978; 1982; 1986; 222382 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Bread and Puppet Theater, 1974; undated; 222383 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - David Cale, undated; 222384 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Channel Z, 1986; undated; 222385 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Ping Chong, 1982; 1984; 1988; 1992; undated; 222386 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Lucinda Childs, undated; 222387 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Remy Charlip, 1980; 1984; 222388 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Merce Cunningham Dance Studio, 1977; 1982; 1984; 222389 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Tricia Brown, 1982; 1985; 1987-1989; 1990; 222390 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Contact Improvisation, 1975; 1978; 1984; 1988; 1990; 1997; undated; 222391 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Quentin Crisp, 2000; 222392 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Blanche Evan, 1964; 1974-1977; 1980-1982; undated; 222393 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Ellen Fisher, 1983-1984; 1984-1988; undated; 222394 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Simone Forti, 1979; 1988; 1995; 1998; undated; 222395 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Philip Glass, 1983; 222396 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Grand Union, undated; 222397 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Spalding Gray, 1980-1981; 222398 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Holly Hughes, undated; 222399 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Bill Jones, 1990; 222400 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Paul Langland, 1968-1985; 222401 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Paul Langland, 1986-1995; 222402 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Paul Langland, 1996-2000; 222403 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Paul Langland, 2001-2006; 222404 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Paul Langland, undated; 222405 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Paul Langland, undated; 222406 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Daniel Lepkoff, 1979; 1987-1989; undated; 222407 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - The Living Theater, 1989; 222408 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Diane Madden, 1986; 1989; undated; 222409 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Nina Martin, 1984-1985; 1989-1990; undated; 222410 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Taylor Mead, undated; 222411 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Tim Miller, 1984; undated; 222412 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Meredith Monk [1 of 2], 1974; 1979; 1981; 1983-2005; 222413 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Meredith Monk [2 of 2], 1974-2006; 2005; 2008; 222414 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Meredith Monk and Ping Chong [1 of 2], 1979-1986; undated; 222415 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Meredith Monk and Ping Chong [2 of 2], 1976; 1979; 222416 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Mark Morris, 1988; 222417 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Mary Overlie, 1977; 1981; 1987; 1998; undated; 222418 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Steve Paxton, undated; 222419 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Steve Petronio, 1982; 1984; 1987-1988; undated; 222420 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Rediculous Theatrical Company, undated; 222421 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Steve Reich, 1977; 222422 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Lily Tomlin, 1986; 222423 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Diane Torr, 1988; 1992; undated; 222424 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Peter Van Riper, circa 1979; 222425 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - David Zambrano, 1986-1988; 2000; undated; 222426 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Subseries B: Venues, 1974-2011; 222545
    - BAM [Brooklyn Academy of Music], 1979; 1982-1984; 1986-1988; undated; 222427 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Dance Theater Workshop [1 of 2], 1982-1989; 1993-1998; undated; 222428 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Dance Theather Worshop [2 of 2], 1982-1989; 1993; 1998; undated; 222429 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Danspace, 1983-1988; 1990; 1996-1997; 1999; undated; 222430 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - La Mama [1 of 2], 1987-1989; 2001; 2008; undated; 222431 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - La Mama [2 of 2], 2001; 2008; undated; 222432 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Movement Research, 1978-1979; 1983; 1985; 1987-1988; 1993; 1998; 2003; 2004; 2008; 2011; undated; 222433 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - NYU Experimental Theater Wing/Tisch School of the Arts [1 of 2], 1982-1984; 1998; undated; 222434 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - NYU Experimental Theater Wing/Tisch School of the Arts [2 of 2], 1998; 2003-2011; undated; 222435 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - PS 122, 1981; 1983-1984; 1988-1989; 1990; undated; 222436 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Venues A-B, 1974; 1977-1978; 1981-1984; 1988; 1990; 1998-1999; 2001-2007; undated; 222437 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Venues C, 1978-1984; 1987-1989; 1993; 1999; 2005; 2009; undated; 222438 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Venues D-G, 1976-1989; 2002-2003; undated; 222439 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Venues H-J, 1979; 1986-1989; 1990; 1992; 2000-2003; undated; 222440 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Venues K-M, 1975; 1978-1988; 1995; 1999; 2004; 2008; undated; 222441 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Venues N-P, 1973; 1978; 1980-1989; 2001; 2005; 2011; 2012; undated; 222442 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Venues S-Z, 1976; 1982; 1988-1989; undated; 222443 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Venues, 1975; 1977; 1980; 1982; 1986-1989; 2002; undated; 222444 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified Venues, 1979-1980; 1984; 1987; 1988; undated; 222445 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Series V: Allan Wayne Material, 1926-1943, 1998-2004, undated; 221375
  Series V contains both material belonging to Allan Wayne and material created by Paul Langland regarding his teaching of Allan Wayne's technique. The material belonging to Allan Wanye consists largely of dance programs featuring Wayne as a dancer. The material created by Paul Langland consists of notes and flyers regarding his classes on "Allan Wayne Work," as well as some biographical information on Allan Wayne
  Arrangement
  The arrangement of Series V reflects Paul Langland's original arrangement of the material.
  - Allan Wayne Material, 1926-1932; 1941; 2000; 2001; 2004; undated; 224046 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Allan Wayne Material, 1998; 2000; 2002; 2004; undated; 224047 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    The material in this folder seems to correspond to Tapes 1-12 in Series Vi: Video.
  - [Allan Wayne Dance Programs], 1926-1943; 224048 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - [Allan Wayne Photo Album], undated; 224049 (Binder 18)
- Series VI: Video recordings, 1977-2004, undated; 203302
  Series VI consists largely of video recordings of Paul Langland's performances. It includes recordings of both Paul Langland's choreography as well as his performances with the Meredith Monk Company, and other dance collaborations. It includes complete recordings as well as some unedited material.
  Series VI also includes three films.
  Series VI is arranged chronologically. Undated material is arranged alphabetically following the dated material.
  - Subseries A: Video Elements, 1977-2004, undated; 203304
    - Quarry: An opera by Meredith Monk performance at BAM, January 10, 1977; ID: 253.0011; 203316 (Box 34, Case 253.0011)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 1 hour 27 minutes
      Original format: VHS
      Existence and Location of Copies
      DVD access copy available.
      Conditions Governing Access
      Currently available.
    - The Travelogue Series, Roudabout Theatre, New York City, March 1977 - Tape 1 of 3, ID: 253.0012; 203317 (Box 34, Case 253.0012)
      Duration: 1 hour 3 minutes
    - The Travelogue Series, Roundabout Theatre, New York City - Tape 2 of 3, March 1977; ID: 253.0013; 203318 (Box 34, Case 253.0013)
      Duration: 43 minutes
    - The Travelogue Series, Roundabout Theatre, New York City, March 1977 - Tape 3 of 3, ID: 253.0014; 203319 (Box 34, Case 253.0014)
      Format: VHS
      Duration: 00:23:00
      Access DVD available.
    - Recent Ruins at LaMama, November 1979; ID: 253.0015; 203320 (Box 34, Case 253.0015)
      Duration: 48 minutes
    - Meredith Monk Vocal Ensemble, Dolmen Music at Washington Hall Performance Gallery, January 17, 1982; ID: 253.0017; 203322 (Box 34, Case 253.0017)
      Duration: 22 minutes
    - Speciman Days at The Public Theater, February 24, 1982; ID: 253.0197; 205264 (Box 37, Case 253.0197)
      Duration: 29 minutes
    - Turtle Dreams (Waltz), 1983; ID: 253.0019; 203324 (Box 34, Folder 253.0019)
      Duration: 26 minutes
    - Fame and Money, Choreography Fellowship Application Support Tape, May 11, 1984; ID: 253.0020; 203325 (Box 34, Case 253.0020)
      Duration: 9 minutes
    - Emotional Corridors, Channel Z Master, January 1984; ID: 253.0198; 205265 (Box 37, Case 253.0198)
      Duration: 8 minutes
    - Channel Z Number 1, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 28, 1984; ID: 253.0199; 205266 (Box 37, Case 253.0199)
      Duration: 47 minutes
    - Channel Z Number 2, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 28, 1984; ID: 253.0200; 205267 (Box 37, Case 253.0200)
    - Channel Z Number 3, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 29, 1984; ID: 253.0201; 205268 (Box 37, Case 253.0201)
      Duration: 51 minutes
    - Channel Z Number 4, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 30, 1984; ID: 253.0202; 205269 (Box 37, Case 253.0202)
      Duration: 1 hour 6 minutes
    - Channel Z Number 5, Ethnic Performance Rehearsal, 1984; ID: 253.0203; 205270 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0203)
      Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
    - Channel Z Number 6, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 30, 1984; ID: 253.0204; 205271 (Box 37, Case 253.0204)
      Duration: 53 minutes
    - Z Boys, Jeff Turtletaub Edit, October 19, 1984; ID: 253.0205; 205272 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0205)
    - Fame and Money, Dance Theatre Workshop, November 25, 1984; ID: 253.0021; 203326 (Box 34, Case 253.0021)
      Duration: 4 minutes
    - Circa 1950-1951, Dance Theatre Workshop, November 1984; ID: 253.0032; 203337 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0032, Case 253.0032)
      Duration: 31 minutes
    - "Eddie" Benefit for the Homeless, 1984; ID: 253.0022; 203327 (Box 34, Case 253.0022)
      Duration: 12 minutes
    - Randy Warshaw, Sunday Nite, January 20, 1985; ID: 253.0206; 205273 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0206, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0206)
      Duration: 35 minutes
    - Molly [MISSING], November 26, 1985; ID: 253.0208; 205275 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0208)
      Original format: 3/4 in. Umatic
    - Laff at the Fags, by Scott Heron and Eric Paulo, 1985; ID: 253.0023; 203328 (Box 34, Case 253.0023)
      Duration: 32 minutes
    - 1. Rapture 2.Candle Dance 3. Fame and Money. Munich and Erlangen, Germany, March 1986; ID: 253.0024; 203329 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0024)
    - 1. Rapture 2. Candle Solo. Munich, April 1986; ID: 253.0025; 203330 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0025)
    - 1. Rapture 2. The Candle Solo. Munich and Erlangen, Germany, April 1986; ID: 253.0154; 203547 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0154)
    - Rapture, etc. Master. Munich and Erlangen, Germany, April 1986; ID: 253.0007; 203312 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0007, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0007)
      Duration: 1 hour 23 minutes
      Original format: Video 8mm
    - Channel Z-- 1. Pepsico Festival 2. Z Boys Video 3.-- PS122, February 1986; ID: 253.0207; 205274 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0207)
      Original format: DVD
    - Tom Lyman, January 31, 1987; ID: 253.0026; 203331 (Box 34, Case 253.0026)
    - Dances in the Environs, Global Village Artist-in-Residence Grants Application-- 1.Man and Machine 2. Kinetic Fairy Tale, September 1, 1987; ID: 253.0209; 205276 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0209)
      Duration: 20 minutes
    - Combing the Will, December 1987; ID: 253.0027; 203332 (Box 34, Case 253.0027)
      Duration: 19 minutes
      Scope and Contents
      Participants: Barbara Hofrenning
    - Aquarium. Michelle, Left Eye, Right Monitor, April 28, 1988; ID: 253.0028; 203333 (Box 34, Case 253.0028)
      Duration: 33 minutes
    - Aquarium. Elisa, Right Eye, Left Monitor, April 28, 1988; ID: 253.0029; 203334 (Box 34, Case 253.0029)
      Duration: 7 minutes
    - Emotional Corridors, The Next Generation., April 28, 1988; ID: 253.0030; 203335 (Box 34, Case 253.0030)
      Duration: 14 minutes
    - Emotional Corridors, The Next Generation. New York University Experimental Theatre Wing Movement Track, May 5, 1988; ID: 253.0031; 203336 (Box 34, Case 253.0031)
      Duration: 1 hour 8 minutes
    - Section 6 Movement Track Performance, NYU Experimental Theatre Wing, May 5, 1988; ID: 253.0033; 203338 (Box 34, Case 253.0033)
      Duration: 1 hour 53 minutes
    - Kitchen Concert, December 1988; ID: 253.0034; 203339 (Box 34, Case 253.0034)
      Duration: 28 minutes
      Credit: Mary Overlie
    - Paul Langland Excerpts-- 1. Jungle Breath 2. Channel Z 3. Man and Machine 4. Eddie 5. Fame and Money, 1988; ID: 253.0035; 203340 (Box 34, Case 253.0035)
      Duration: 36 minutes
      Participants: Jungle Breath - Daniel Lepkoff
    - Jungle Breath, 1988-1989; ID: 253.0211; 205278 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0211)
      Duration: 27 minutes
    - Paul Solos, Movement Track Improvisations, 1988; ID: 253.0039; 203344 (Box 34, Case 253.0039)
      Duration: 60 minutes
    - 2 Works: 1. Jungle Breath 2. Domestic Virtue, January 1989; ID: 253.0041; 203346 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0041)
      Participants: Jungle Breath - Daniel Lepkoff, Domestic Virtue, Barbara Hofrenning
    - Hofrenning/Langland, Edited Domestic Virtue, February 1, 1989; ID: 253.0042; 203347 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0042)
      Duration: 10 minutes
      Orignial format: VHS
    - Excerpts- 1. Boomerang 2. Domestic Virtue, or Bingo Rocks the House, April 1989; ID: 253.0043; 203348 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0043)
      Participants: Domestic Virtue, Barbara Hofrenning
    - Excerpts- 1. Boomerang 2. Rapture 3. Domestic Virtue or Bingo Rocks the House 4. Jungle Breath, May 1989; ID: 253.0044; 203349 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0044)
      Duration: 25 minutes
    - Pool Pictures, August 27, 1989; ID: 253.0045; 203350 (Box 35, Case 253.0045)
      Duration: 49 minutes
    - Jungle Breath/Bone Yard. Hillsdale, New York, October 21, 1989; ID: 253. 0046; 203351 (Box 35, Case 253.0046)
      Duration: 1 hour 10 minutes
    - Paul Langland American Choreographer Awards Application 1. Boomerang 2. Rapture 3. Domestic Virtue 4. Jungle Breath, 1989; ID: 253.0047; 203352 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0047)
      Participants: Jungle Breath - Daniel Lepkoff; Domestic Virtue - Barbara Hofrenning
    - Waterfall, 1989; ID: 253. 0049; 203354 (Box 35, Case 253.0049)
    - Section 4 Footage, Work Tape, Experimental Theatre Wing, 1989; ID: 253.0050; 203355 (Box 35, Case 253.0050)
      Duration: 1 hour 22 minutes
    - Original Unedited Footage and Edited Pieces, 1989, 1990; ID: 253.0051; 203356 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0051)
    - Paul and Gail Worktape, MM Collage, January 1990; ID: 253.0052; 203357 (Box 35, Case 253.0052)
      Duration: 2 hours 2 minutes
    - Rudie to Paul, Project Diary, February 1990; ID: 253.0053; 203358 (Box 35, Case 253.0053)
      Duration: 45 minutes
    - Art Matters Grant Application, Three Pieces 1. Waterfall 2. I Feel I Am 3. Jungle Breath, February 1990; ID: 253.0210; 205277 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0210)
      Duration: 11 minutes
    - 1. Man and Machine 2. Waterfall, February 14, 1990; ID: 253.0054; 203359 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0054)
      Original format: Betamax
    - 1.Waterfall 2. Jonah, Performance Edit, April 27, 1990; ID: 253.0058; 203364 (Box 35, Case 253.0058)
      Duration: 16 minutes
    - The Ghost of a Flea, Hadley Copy, May 6, 1990; ID: 253.0059; 203365 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0059, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0059)
      Duration: 1 hour 12 minutes
    - Excerpts from the Ghost of a Flea (Choreographer Fellowship Application Tape), May 25, 1990; ID: 253.0060; 203366 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0060)
    - The Ghost of a Flea at P.S. 122 (Edited Master), May 26, 1990; ID: 253.0212; 205279 (Box 37, Case 253.0212)
      Duration: 52 minutes
      Format: 3/4 in. Umatic
    - The Ghost of a Flea at P.S. 122 (Master), May 26, 1990; ID: 253.0214; 205281 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0214)
    - Diary, Venezuela. Danny, Paul, Gail, February-July 1990; ID: 253.0057; 203362 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0057)
    - Spectra. Hillsdale, New York, August 18, 1990; ID: 253.0063; 203369 (Box 35, Case 253.0063)
      Participants: Lisa Nelson - Dodo, David Zambrano - Carmen
    - Arts Panorama, August 23, 1990; ID: 253.0064; 203370 (Box 35, Case 253.0064)
    - Untitled, August 1990; ID: 253.0062; 203368 (Box 35, Case 253.0062)
      Duration: 2 hour 2 minutes
    - Paul Langland at the Theatre Thala, Gothenburg, Sweden, October 26, 1990; ID: 253.0065; 203371 (Box 35, Case 253.0065)
      Duration: 34 minutes
    - Location of Love by Mary Overlie - Dance Collection, December 19, 1990; ID: 253.0066; 203372 (Box 35, Case 253.0066)
    - Jungle Breath, 1990; ID: 253.0056; 203361 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0056)
      Duration: 18 minutes
    - Jonah, 1990; ID: 253.0215; 205282 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0215)
    - Normal Kansas, Experimental Theatre Wing Mainstage II (Copy of Super 8mm film), April 1991; ID: 253.0068; 203374 (Box 35, Case 253.0068)
      Duration: 1 hour 26 minutes
    - Downtown Upstate, Wide Angle, October 25, 1991; ID: 253.0069; 203375 (Box 35, Case 253.0069)
      Duration: 1 hour 24 minutes
    - Downtown Upstate, 1991; ID: 253.0073; 203379 (Box 35, Case 253.0073)
    - We Interrupt This Program...Day Without Art, Live Television Broadcast., 1991; ID: 253.0070; 203376 (Box 35, Case 253.0070)
    - A Voice For All, NYU Experimental Theatre Wing - AIDS Week, Tape 1 of 2, 1991; ID: 253.0071; 203377 (Box 35, Case 253.0071)
      Duration: 2 hours
    - A Voice For All, NYU Experimental Theatre Wing - AIDS Week, Tape 2 of 2, 1991; ID: 253.0072; 203378 (Box 35, Case 253.0072)
      Duration: 54 minutes
    - Paul Langland - ETW Class, 1992; ID: 253.0074; 203380 (Box 35, Case 253.0074)
      Duration: 24 minutes
    - 1.Angels and Apes Trio, NYC 2. Saint Marks Church Trio, 1. April 1993 2. December 1993; ID: 253.0075; 203381 (Box 35, Case 253.0075)
    - Full Flora Smak, New York University, 1994; ID: 253.0076; 203382 (Box 35, Case 253.0076)
    - Almost Rapture - Rehearsal, November 28, 1995; ID: 253.0079; 203385 (Box 35, Case 253.0079)
    - Dybbuks and Chicken Soup by Blondell Cummings, 1995; ID: 253.0080; 203386 (Box 35, Case 253.0080)
      DVD access copy avialable.
    - Untitled Duet -Paul Langland and Brendan McCall, DanceFest 5, 1995; ID: 253.0081; 203387 (Box 36, Case 253.0081)
      Duration: 3 minutes
    - Almost Rapture - Rehearsal Master, January 18, 1996; ID: 253.0216; 205283 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0216)
    - Almost Rapture at Danspace at Saint Marks Church, New York City, January 21, 1996; ID: 252.0082; 203388 (Box 35, Media ID: 252.0082, Box Digitized Access Files, File 252.0082)
    - 33 Fainting Spells, The Uninvited, On the Boards, Seattle, Washington, January 26, 1996; ID: 253.0083; 203389 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0083, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0083)
      Credit: Dayna Hanson and Gaelen Hanson
      Duration: 59 minutes
    - Almost Rapture and Other Dance Surprises, Danspace Project- 1.-- Normal Dog Time 2. Land Mind 3. Almost Rapture (Master), February 23, 1997; ID: 253.0001; 203306 (Box 34, Case 253.0001)
      Original format: 3/4" Umatic
    - Section Seven Class Showing Choreography, March 1998; ID: 253.0085; 203391 (Box 35, Case 253.0085)
    - 1. Almost Rapture, Solo 2. Honor, Excerpt. Dixon Place., April 1998; ID: 253.0084; 203390 (Box 35, Case 253.0084)
      Duration: 13 minutes
    - Honor, Tisch NYU-Danspace Project (Master), May 17, 1998; ID: 253.0218; 205285 (Box 38, Case 253.0218)
      Duration: 46 minutes
    - Tape 1, AW Warm Up, Cellular Introduction, Celluar Discussion, November 1998; ID: 253.0219; 205286 (Box 39, Case 253.0219)
      Duration: 1 hour 40 minutes
    - Tape 2, November 1998; ID: 253.0220; 205287 (Box 39, Case 253.0220)
      Duration: 1 hour 30 minutes
    - Tape 4, November 18, 1998; ID: 253.0221; 205288 (Box 39, Case 253.0221)
      Duration: 1 hours 49 minutes
    - Tape 5, Four Fluid Reviews and Comp. Review, Cellular, Lymph, Int. Cell, Fascia, November 20, 1998; ID: 253.0222; 205289 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0222, Case 253.0222)
      Duration: 1 hour 19 minutes
    - Tape 6, AW Wall Work and Dancing, November 1998; ID: 253.0223; 205290 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0223, Case 253.0223)
      Duration: 1 hour 49 minutes